- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
Kids:
Aye, aye, Captain!
孩子们：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
Kids:
Aye, aye, Captain!
孩子们：
是啊是啊，队长！
- ♪ Ohh... ♪
- ♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
Kids:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
孩子们：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
- ♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
kids:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
孩子们：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ If nautical nonsense
be something you wish ♪
- ♪ 如果航海废话
成为你想要的东西♪
kids:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
孩子们：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
- ♪ 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
kids: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
孩子们：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
All:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
[flute plays]
[长笛演奏]
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[light melodic music]
[轻快的旋律音乐]
♪ ♪
[angry clamoring]
[愤怒的叫喊]
- Huh?
- 啊？
What's the meaning of this,
Mr. Squidward?
这句话有什么意义
章鱼哥先生？
- Don't ask me.
- 别问我。
Ask SpongeBob.
问海绵宝宝。
- [vocalizing]
- [发声]
- Hey, um, Mom, you don't need
- 嘿，嗯，妈妈，你不需要
to cut the crust off
the Krabby Patty.
切掉外壳
蟹肉饼。
Ha, we are making fast food.
哈，我们正在做快餐。
- Love takes time, darling.
- 爱需要时间，亲爱的。
Now hand me a tomato so I can
carve it into a rose garnish.
现在递给我一个西红柿，这样我就可以
将其雕刻成玫瑰装饰。
- SpongeBob!
- 海绵宝宝！
What in blue blazes
is going on in...
蓝色火焰里有什么
正在发生在...
oh, hello, Mrs. SquarePants.
哦，你好，方裤夫人。
- Well, hello, Eugene.
- 嗯，你好，尤金。
I'm learning how
to make Krabby Patties.
我正在学习如何
制作蟹黄饼。
- Oh, how lovely.
- 哦，多么可爱啊。
Uh, may I borrow your son
for just a moment?
呃，我可以借用你的儿子吗
就一会儿？
What is going on here, boy-o?
这是怎么回事，男孩？
Why is your mother
in the kitchen?
为什么是你妈妈
在厨房里？
Just take a look at that crowd!
只要看看那群人就知道了！
- This is why I never go out
to eat anymore!
- 这就是我从不出门的原因
不再吃东西了！
- Your mommy has no business
at my business.
- 你妈妈没闲事
在我的生意上。
Send her home.
- Oh, but Mr. Krabs,
送她回家。
- 哦，但是蟹老板先生，
the official employee calendar
says it's...
官方员工日历
说这是...
Bring Your Mom to Work Day.
带你妈妈去上班日。
- Ha, too bad I forgot.
- 哈，可惜我忘了。
Boy, that would have been awful.
孩子，那真是太糟糕了。
- Oh, it shivers me timbers
to think what a disaster
- 哦，它让我发抖
想想真是一场灾难
my mom would make
if she was here.
我妈妈会做
如果她在这里的话。
[both laugh]
[两人都笑了]
- Ahem!
- 咳咳！
- Don't you worry, fellas.
I invited your moms too.
- 别担心，伙计们。
我也邀请了你妈妈。
- What?
- 什么？
[strained] How thoughtful
of you, SpongeBob.
[紧张]想得真周到
你，海绵宝宝。
- Well, we're here,
- 嗯，我们到了，
so stop your horseplay
and show me what you do.
所以停止你的恶作剧吧
并告诉我你做了什么。
- Mother, you're
embarrassing me.
- 妈妈，你是
让我难堪。
Ow, ow, ow, ow!
- [chuckling]
噢，噢，噢，噢！
- [轻笑]
[gasps]
[喘气]
- I don't know what
you're chuckling about, Eugene.
- 我不知道什么
你在笑，尤金。
There's wasted money
everywhere I look!
有浪费钱的
我到处看！
[sizzles]
[嘶嘶声]
When was the last time you
changed the oil in this fryer?
上次你是什么时候
换了这个炸锅里的油吗？
- We change it every day, ma'am.
- 我们每天都会更换，女士。
- Waste!
- 浪费！
Should be but once a year.
每年应该只有一次。
[sloshes]
[晃动]
Real tomato ketchup.
Waste!
真正的番茄酱。
浪费！
I bet in your latrine
you use two-ply toilet paper.
我打赌在你的厕所里
你使用两层卫生纸。
- Ha, we use one-ply.
- 哈，我们用的是一层。
- As if it grows on trees.
Waste!
- 就好像它长在树上一样。
浪费！
It should be half-ply.
应该是半层的。
Your profits
would be much higher
您的利润
会高得多
if you stopped spending
willy-nilly.
如果你停止消费
无论愿意与否。
- Yes, Mama.
- 是的，妈妈。
- Remember to smile, son.
- 记得微笑，儿子。
- [grumbles]
- [抱怨]
- Where's my food?
- 我的食物在哪里？
- I'm sorry for the delay, sir.
- 抱歉耽搁了，先生。
Your order will be up soon.
您的订单很快就会完成。
- I didn't say
lose your disdain.
-我没说
失去你的蔑视。
- [growls]
- And don't slouch.
- [咆哮]
- 并且不要无精打采。
You'll ruin your spine.
你会毁掉你的脊椎。
- I'm an invertebrate, Mother!
- 我是无脊椎动物，妈妈！
- And no back talk.
- 并且没有顶嘴。
- Yes, Mother.
- 是的，妈妈。
- Nice disdain.
- 很好的蔑视。
But save it for the customers.
- [sighs]
但还是留给顾客吧。
- [叹气]
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
Order up for Old Man Jenkins.
为老詹金斯订购。
One Krabby Patty
with crust removed
一份蟹肉饼
去除外壳
and one side salad.
和一份沙拉。
- I ordered fries, not a salad.
- 我点了薯条，不是沙拉。
- The fries are in the salad.
- 薯条在沙拉里。
- Okay, I'll try it.
- 好吧，我会尝试一下。
But only 'cause I'm so hungry.
但只是因为我太饿了。
[chomps]
[咀嚼]
Aha!
[all gasp]
啊哈！
[全都喘气]
It reminds me of my mother's
cooking when I was but a boy.
这让我想起了我母亲的
我小时候做饭。
I'm filled with childish glee!
我心里充满了童趣！
[giggles]
[咯咯笑]
- Mm.
- 毫米。
- I made everyone's orders.
- 我下达了每个人的命令。
- Huh?
- [laughs]
- 啊？
- [笑]
- My mom doesn't understand
fast food... not the way I do.
- 我妈妈不明白
快餐...不是我的方式。
Her cooking takes forever,
because she adds love.
她的烹饪需要很长时间，
因为她增添了爱。
- You mean there's no love
in this Krabby Patty?
- 你的意思是没有爱
在这个蟹肉饼里？
Now all I taste is the fast.
现在我只尝到了斋戒的滋味。
I demand a refund!
我要求退款！
- Give me some love.
- Yeah, me too!
- 给我一些爱。
- 是的，我也是！
[angry clamoring]
[愤怒的叫喊]
- Okay, that's enough.
- 好吧，够了。
There'll be no refunds.
不会有退款。
You see, there is love here.
你看，这里有爱。
My love for your money.
[heart thumping]
我对你的钱的爱。
[心跳]
Mwah.
哇。
You don't want
to break us up, do ya?
你不想要
来拆散我们，是吗？
- Give me my money back!
- Where's the love?
- 把钱还给我！
- 爱在哪里？
[screeching]
[all groan]
[尖叫声]
[全都呻吟]
- Clearly, our sons aren't
working hard enough.
- 显然，我们的儿子不是
工作足够努力。
Believe me when I say no one
is more disappointed than we,
当我说没有人时请相信我
比我们更失望的是
their mothers.
他们的母亲。
- We thought
we taught them better.
- 我们以为
我们教得更好。
- To avert this disaster,
- 为了避免这场灾难，
we're going
to take over the restaurant
我们要去
接管餐厅
and show our boys how it's done.
并向我们​​的孩子们展示这是如何做到的。
- But Mama!
- Zip it!
- 但是妈妈！
- 拉上拉链！
And to the shame corner
with you three.
到羞耻的角落
和你们三个。
All: Aww.
全体：哇。
- Now time to spruce
this place up.
- 现在是时候修剪一下了
这个地方起来。
- "Mama Krabs
Home-style Cooking"?
- “蟹妈妈
家庭式烹饪”？
This is gonna be a disaster.
这将是一场灾难。
Look at what they did
to me restaurant.
看看他们做了什么
给我的餐厅。
[bright music]
[明亮的音乐]
- I think the place looks homey.
- 我觉得这个地方看起来很温馨。
- If I wanted "homey,"
I'd stay at home.
- 如果我想要“温馨”
我会呆在家里。
This is costing me a fortune.
[cash register dings]
这让我损失了一大笔钱。
[收银机叮叮声]
- Actually, Mrs. SquarePants
had all this stuff
- 事实上，方裤夫人
拥有所有这些东西
in the trunk of her boat.
在她的船的后备箱里。
- A mother is always prepared.
- 母亲总是做好准备。
- Eventually, our moms
will crash and burn.
- 最终，我们的妈妈
会崩溃并燃烧。
And then we'll reclaim
the Krusty Krab.
然后我们会回收
蟹堡王。
- Looks like it's gonna happen
sooner than later.
- 看来这会发生
宜早不宜迟。
Look who just arrived.
看看谁刚到。
- [grunts grotesquely]
- Bubble Bass.
- [怪诞地咕哝]
- 泡泡鲈鱼。
- Every mom's nightmare.
- 每个妈妈的噩梦。
- Bubby, you forgot your doll
on the boat.
- 巴比，你忘记带娃娃了
在船上。
- Mom!
- 妈妈！
It's an action figure,
not a doll.
这是一个动作人物，
不是洋娃娃。
- We're doomed.
- 我们注定了。
- Welcome to Mama Krabs'.
- 欢迎来到蟹妈妈家。
Right this way.
- [grumbles]
就这样。
- [抱怨]
- Here's your menus.
- 这是你的菜单。
- Interesting.
- 有趣的。
We shall see if
this new management
我们将看看是否
这个新的管理
can stand up to my scrutiny.
经得起我的推敲。
I will have one of every...
huh?
我每样都会有一个...
嗯？
Ow!
噢！
- We'll both have
the early-bird special.
- 我们都会有
早鸟特惠。
- Mother,
I'm going to get a soda.
- 妈妈，
我要去买一瓶苏打水。
[exclaims]
[惊呼]
[hums happily]
[高兴地哼哼]
Hmm?
[yelps]
唔？
[尖叫声]
Mom!
妈妈！
- Soda straws are dangerous.
- 苏打水吸管很危险。
You'll put your eye out.
你会把你的眼睛挖出来。
Use this instead.
- [gasps]
用这个代替。
- [喘气]
Ooh! Ga-ga.
哦！嘎嘎。
I mean, uh, so embarrassing.
我的意思是，呃，太尴尬了。
[burps]
[打嗝]
- Here you go.
- 干得好。
- Ooh.
- Two Krabby Patty casseroles.
- 哦。
- 两份蟹肉饼砂锅菜。
I even cut it
into bite-sized pieces.
我还把它剪掉了
切成一口大小的碎片。
- That's just how
my boy likes it.
- 就是这样
我的男孩喜欢它。
- Enjoy!
- 享受！
- Of course that mama's boy
would like it here.
- 当然是妈妈的儿子
会喜欢这里的。
- Uh, guys, look!
- 呃，伙计们，看！
It seems like everyone
is liking it here.
看来大家
很喜欢这里。
[contented chatter]
[心满意足的闲聊]
- You've got some smudge.
- 你身上有一些污迹。
- Danke.
- 丹克。
- I don't believe it.
- 我不相信。
They're a success.
他们是成功的。
- Well, of course they are.
- 嗯，当然是。
Look how hard they're working.
看看他们有多努力。
- I actually feel kind of guilty
- 我其实感到有点内疚
seeing them do all the work.
看到他们做所有的工作。
- How pathetic.
- 多么可悲啊。
You three clearly don't know
how to appreciate
你们三个显然不知道
如何欣赏
the smothering embrace
of motherly love.
令人窒息的拥抱
的母爱。
- And what do you suggest?
- 你有什么建议？
- Are these premises equipped
with a basement?
- 这些场所是否配备齐全
有地下室吗？
- All right, here we are.
- 好吧，我们到了。
- Gentlemen, I present
the fortress of solitude
- 先生们，我介绍
孤独的堡垒
for adult children.
对于成年儿童。
- It's a junk-filled basement.
- 这是一个堆满垃圾的地下室。
- Oh, you see junk.
- 哦，你看到垃圾了。
I see...
我懂了...
- [gasps]
- [喘气]
A hangout lounge!
一个聚会休息室！
- Correct.
- 正确的。
- Well, it's better
than the shame corner.
- 嗯，这样更好了
比羞耻角。
- I guess.
- 我猜。
- Down here,
you can spend your time
- 在这里，
你可以花时间
doing whatever you want.
做你想做的事。
Reading comics,
playing video games,
看漫画，
玩电子游戏，
complaining on the Internet.
[dolphin chirps]
在网上抱怨。
[海豚鸣叫声]
- Your life choices are lame,
- 你的人生选择是蹩脚的，
but I like the overall concept.
但我喜欢整体概念。
- And with your mother upstairs,
- 你妈妈在楼上，
snacks are just a holler away.
小吃距离酒店仅一步之遥。
- Ooh, my mom loves
to make snacks.
- 哦，我妈妈喜欢
做零食。
What else can you teach us,
你还能教我们什么
oh wise sage
of the slacker ways?
噢，明智的圣人
比较懒惰的方法？
- Alas, my time with you is
at an end.
- 唉，我和你在一起的时间是
在结束时。
I have been a good boy,
and my mother is taking me
我一直是个好孩子
我妈妈带着我
for ice cream
in three, two, one.
用于冰淇淋
三、二、一。
[yelps]
[尖叫声]
I'm ready for my ice cream,
Mommy.
我已经准备好吃冰淇淋了
妈妈。
- Bye, girls!
- 再见，女孩们！
- Come back soon, you hear.
- 快点回来，你听到了。
- Well, I guess
we can give it a try.
- 嗯，我想
我们可以尝试一下。
[clears throat]
Mo-om!
[清嗓子]
唷唷！
[8-bit sounds and music]
[8位声音和音乐]
- [grumbles]
- [laughs]
- [抱怨]
- [笑]
Mom, nachos!
妈妈，玉米片！
[laughs]
- [groans]
[笑]
- [呻吟]
- [laughs]
- Hey, watch the fort!
- [笑]
- 嘿，注意堡垒！
- Mom!
- Ma!
- 妈妈！
- 妈！
- Mom!
- 妈妈！
- Mom.
- Mom!
- 妈妈。
- 妈妈！
- Hey, Ma!
- 嘿，妈妈！
[sleepy murmurs]
- Mommy, Mommy.
[困倦的低语]
- 妈妈，妈妈。
- Mommy, Mommy, Mommy.
- 妈妈，妈妈，妈妈。
- I've never slept better
in me life.
- 我从来没有睡得这么好过
在我的生活中。
Last night made me feel
like a kid again.
昨晚让我感觉
又像个孩子了。
- [exhales]
So that's what it's like
- [呼气]
所以就是这样的
to have a childhood.
拥有一个童年。
- Aww, you guys are
the best buddies
- 哇，你们是
最好的朋友
a kid could ever have.
一个孩子可能会拥有。
[rumbling]
[隆隆声]
- I'm hungry.
- 我饿了。
Mom, breakfast!
妈妈，早餐啦！
[crickets chirp]
[蟋蟀鸣叫]
- Guys, I think
something's wrong.
- 伙计们，我想
出问题了。
- Agreed, lad.
We better go check.
- 同意，小伙子。
我们最好去检查一下。
[grunting, laughter]
[咕哝声、笑声]
- Oh, yeah.
- 哦，是的。
[relaxed chatter]
[轻松的闲聊]
- [snickers]
- Booyah!
- [窃笑]
- 嘘！
- [snoring]
- [打鼾]
- What in tarnation?
- 塔尼翁什么？
Who are these bums?
这些流浪汉是谁？
- Hey, kids.
- 嘿，孩子们。
- Oh, there you are, Eugene.
- 哦，你来了，尤金。
Go fix me one of
those Krabbity Patties
去给我修一个
那些蟹肉饼
you're always going on about.
你总是喋喋不休。
All: Dad?
全体：爸爸？
- Oh!
- 哦！
That's right.
这是正确的。
Today is Bring Your Dad
to Work Day.
今天带你爸爸来
到工作日。
- Oh, uh, while you're up, son,
could you refill my drink?
- 哦，呃，当你起床的时候，儿子，
你能给我续杯吗？
- And more chips for me, kid.
- 还有更多筹码给我，孩子。
- Any time you're ready with
that Krabbity Patty, son.
- 任何时候你准备好
克拉比蒂·帕蒂，儿子。
- I want my mommy.
- [whimpers]
- 我想要我的妈妈。
- [呜咽]
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
♪ ♪
- I'm glad you can come
to the pet park today, Patrick.
- 我很高兴你能来
今天去宠物公园，帕特里克。
- [muffled muttering]
- [低声嘀咕]
Well, thanks for inviting me.
嗯，谢谢你邀请我。
I can't wait
to see Gary's new tricks!
我等不及了
来看看Gary的新花样吧！
- [meowing]
- [喵喵叫]
- There's nothing more fun
than bringing your pet
- 没有什么比这更好玩的了
比带你的宠物
to a pet park.
去宠物公园。
- SpongeBob!
- 海绵宝宝！
[laughs maniacally]
[疯狂地笑]
I got one of those head things!
我得到了其中一件这样的东西！
- A concussion?
- 脑震荡？
- Yeah.
- 是的。
But also the other thing.
但还有另一件事。
- Oh, a thought.
- 哦，一个想法。
- Yeah, I think
I'd like to have my own pet
- 是的，我想
我想拥有自己的宠物
to bring to the pet park.
带到宠物公园。
- That's a great idea.
- 这是个好主意。
We can stop at the pet store
on the way.
我们可以在宠物店停下来
在路上。
Mm, do any of these pets
pique your fancy?
嗯，养这些宠物吗
激怒你的幻想吗？
- No.
- 不。
Uh-uh. Nope.
呃呃。没有。
Whoa!
哇！
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
♪ ♪
That one!
那个！
I want that one!
That's the pet for me!
我想要那个！
这就是我的宠物！
- Huh.
- 嗯。
All right, go on through.
好吧，继续吧。
Hold it right there!
就稳住那儿吧！
I'm gonna need
to see some proof of pet.
我将需要
查看宠物的一些证明。
- Of course.
- 当然。
- That's a rock.
- 那是一块石头。
- Yeah.
His name is Rolly.
- 是的。
他的名字叫罗利。
- I don't see how
this thing is a pet.
- 我不明白怎么办
这东西是宠物。
- Oh, here.
Take a closer look.
- 哦，在这里。
仔细看看。
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
Oh, yes. He's adorable.
哦是的。他很可爱。
Go right in.
向右进去。
- Thanks.
[laughs]
- 谢谢。
[笑]
Come on, Rolly.
来吧，罗利。
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
- [neighs]
- [嘶嘶声]
- Wow.
- 哇。
Yup, that's my card.
- [laughs]
是的，那是我的卡。
- [笑]
- [giggles]
- [咯咯笑]
Rolly, Rolly, Rolly!
罗利，罗利，罗利！
[winces, laughs]
[畏缩，大笑]
- Oh.
- 哦。
Geode hunting is
a cracking good time.
晶洞狩猎是
一段美好的时光。
[giggles]
[咯咯笑]
Ooh, ha ha!
哦，哈哈！
The perfect crystal
quartz lattice.
完美的水晶
石英晶格。
An exquisite specimen
for my collection.
精美的标本
为了我的收藏。
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
- Rolly, you're
the best rock ever.
- 罗利，你是
有史以来最好的摇滚。
- What the devil?
- 什么鬼？
By Jove.
乔夫。
Such majesty.
如此威严。
That must have quite the geode
inside.
那一定有相当大的晶洞
里面。
[cackles]
[咯咯笑]
- [laughs]
- Tallyho, good chap.
- [笑]
- 塔利霍，好小伙子。
Whoa!
哇！
Perciful Rockhound,
amateur geode enthusiast.
敏锐的岩石猎犬，
业余晶洞爱好者。
- You talk funny.
- 你说话很有趣。
[giggles]
Huh?
[咯咯笑]
啊？
What? What's that, Rolly?
什么？那是什么，罗利？
Uh-huh.
嗯嗯。
Rolly says he wants
to play with you.
罗利说他想要
和你一起玩。
Here you go.
干得好。
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
- Have fun, you two.
- 玩得开心，你们两个。
- Ooh.
- Wow.
- 哦。
- 哇。
- Hey, Patrick. Where's Rolly?
- 嘿，帕特里克。罗利在哪里？
- Oh, he's playing with the
funny mustache man over there.
- 哦，他正在玩
那边有有趣的小胡子男人。
- [muffled muttering]
- [低声嘀咕]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
- Oh, so cute.
- 噢，真可爱。
But that's enough play, Rolly.
但玩够了，罗利。
- [yelps]
- [gasps]
- [尖叫声]
- [喘气]
- Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa!
- 哇，哇，哇，
哇，哇，哇！
Whoa, Rolly!
哇，罗利！
You want to play
with everyone today.
你想玩
今天和大家一起。
Done already?
已经完成了吗？
Oh, who's a good boy?
哦，谁是好孩子？
- Uh, Patrick,
maybe we should leave.
- 呃，帕特里克，
也许我们应该离开。
- Good idea, SpongeBob.
- 好主意，海绵宝宝。
Everybody here is
sleeping anyway.
这里的每个人都是
反正睡觉。
Come on, Rolly!
加油，罗利！
- I will tear that rock asunder.
- 我会把那块岩石撕成碎片。
[cackles]
[咯咯笑]
- What a fun day.
- 多么有趣的一天啊。
Now it's time to do
my favorite thing...
现在是时候做
我最喜欢的东西...
nothing!
没有什么！
[chuckles]
[笑声]
[chomping]
[咀嚼]
- It's the "Sir Urchin
& Snail Fail Show."
- 这是“顽童先生”
＆蜗牛失败秀。”
- [laughs]
- Why, you!
- [笑]
- 为什么，你！
- What'd I do?
- 我做了什么？
- [guffaws]
- [大笑]
[phone beeping]
[电话嘟嘟声]
- [meows]
- [喵]
[phone rings]
[电话铃声]
- SquarePants residence.
- 方裤住宅。
- Oh, SpongeBob.
I don't think Rolly likes TV.
- 哦，海绵宝宝。
我认为罗利不喜欢电视。
[Gary chomping]
He tore up the place.
[加里咀嚼]
他撕毁了这个地方。
- Have you been feeding him?
- 你喂过他吗？
Pets get cranky
if they don't get their food.
宠物脾气暴躁
如果他们没有得到食物。
- Oh, yeah! Oh.
- 哦，是的！哦。
Thanks, buddy.
谢谢，伙计。
- Of course.
- 当然。
- Rolly!
- 罗利！
SpongeBob said you need lots
of food.
海绵宝宝说你需要很多
食物。
Good thing I had this big bag
of cement mix on hand.
还好我有这么大的包
手头的水泥混合物。
Just add water.
只需加水即可。
Huh. Okay.
呵呵。好的。
Bone apple teeth, Rolly.
骨苹果牙，罗利。
Now it's time for my lunch.
现在该吃午饭了。
[vacuum whirs]
[真空呼呼声]
I like it dry.
我喜欢干的。
Huh? Whoa!
啊？哇！
Rolly, you got big.
罗利，你长大了。
SpongeBob?
- Yes?
海绵宝宝？
- 是的？
- I fed Rolly, and he got big!
- 我喂了罗利，他长大了！
Is he dying?
他快死了吗？
- No, you silly.
- 不，你这个傻瓜。
He probably just needs a walk
to go potty.
他可能只是需要散步
去上厕所。
But make sure
he wears his leash.
但请确保
他戴着皮带。
- Okay!
- 好的！
Time for a walk, Rolly.
是时候去散步了，罗利。
The world is your toilet.
世界就是你的厕所。
- [chuckles]
- [轻笑]
My word.
我的话。
How rotund his rock has grown.
他的石头长得多圆啊。
I must pilfer that plump pebble.
我必须偷走那块肥美的鹅卵石。
- [humming]
- [嗡嗡声]
- [whimpers]
- [呜咽]
- Aah!
- 啊啊！
- [screams]
- [尖叫]
- Ooh!
- 哦！
What stinks?
[squelch]
什么臭？
[静噪]
Oh, it's you, Rolly.
哦，是你，罗莉。
Hmm, what am I supposed to do?
嗯，我该怎么办？
[beeping, line trilling]
[嘟嘟声，线路颤音]
Hi, SpongeBob.
嗨，海绵宝宝。
- Hey, Patrick.
- 嘿，帕特里克。
- Ma-mow.
- 妈妈。
- [sniffs, strains]
- [嗅、拉]
Rolly smells like garbage water.
罗利闻起来像垃圾水。
Is he mad at me?
他生我的气吗？
- Of course not.
- 当然不是。
You can take him to a groomer
to freshen him up.
你可以带他去美容师那里
让他精神焕发。
- Oh? Huh.
- 哦？呵呵。
Conveniently Placed
Rock Groomer.
位置方便
岩石美容师。
There's one right here!
这里就有一个！
Thanks, SpongeBob.
谢谢，海绵宝宝。
[chomps]
[咀嚼]
[bright music]
[明亮的音乐]
[groans]
Hmm?
[呻吟]
嗯？
- Good day, sir.
- Huh?
- 美好的一天，先生。
- 啊？
- [snickers]
- [窃笑]
I'm the rock groomer.
我是岩石美容师。
May I take that ample, glorious
collectible rock from you?
我可以接受那充足、光荣的
您的收藏岩石？
Whoa!
哇！
- Rolly needs a bath.
- 罗利需要洗澡。
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
- Aah!
- 啊啊！
At last, the glimmering contents
最后，闪烁的内容
of your sturdy aspects
shall be mine.
你坚强的方面
将是我的。
[growls]
[咆哮]
Huh? Aah, aah!
啊？啊啊啊！
Oh, no! Back, you beast!
哦，不！回来吧，你这个畜生！
Ow! Ow!
噢！噢！
- Oh, finished already?
- 哦，已经结束了吗？
Wow!
哇！
Rolly, you're beautiful!
罗莉，你真美！
I've gotta tell SpongeBob.
我得告诉海绵宝宝。
- Hi again.
- 又嗨了。
- SpongeBob, Rolly
looks prettier than,
- 海绵宝宝、罗利
看起来比,更漂亮
um, a really pretty thing.
嗯，非常漂亮的东西。
You gotta see him.
你一定要见他。
- Well, you should
bring him down
- 嗯，你应该
把他打倒
to the Bikini Bottom Pet Show.
参加比基尼宠物秀。
Gary and I are here now.
加里和我现在就在这里。
[cheers and applause]
[欢呼和掌声]
- Great! See ya there.
- 伟大的！再见。
- [groans weakly]
- [微弱地呻吟]
- Lady, you need a bath.
- 女士，你需要洗澡。
- [moans]
- [呻吟]
[lively music]
[活泼的音乐]
- Yee-haw!
- 哎呀！
- Contestant 24.
- 参赛者24。
- Huh? Oh!
- 啊？哦！
[laughs]
[笑]
[barks]
[吠叫]
His name is Rolly.
他的名字叫罗利。
Isn't he pretty?
他不是很漂亮吗？
- Hmm. What does it do?
- 唔。它有什么作用？
- I'll show you.
- 我会告诉你。
[groans, laughs]
[呻吟，大笑]
♪ ♪
- Whoo! Go, Patrick, go!
Whoo!
- 呼！走吧，帕特里克，走吧！
呼！
- [meows]
- Whoo!
- [喵]
- 呼！
Go, Patrick, go!
走吧，帕特里克，走吧！
[all yelping]
[全都尖叫]
- Ta-da!
- 哒哒！
- Well, it seems
every other contestant
- 嗯，看来
其他所有参赛者
has been eliminated.
已被淘汰。
- I suppose you win...
- 我想你赢了...
by default.
默认情况下。
- We... did it!
- 我们...做到了！
Rolly, you're the best rock...
罗利，你是最好的摇滚......
- Ever!
[cackles]
- 曾经！
[咯咯笑]
Finally, your crystalline cache
is all mine.
最后，你的水晶缓存
都是我的。
[curious mystical music]
[好奇的神秘音乐]
- Rolly!
- 罗利！
Oh, no!
哦，不！
- Ooh.
[pants excitedly]
- 哦。
[兴奋地裤子]
- [roars]
- [咆哮]
- Oh.
G-g-good show, old chap.
- 哦。
干、干、干得好，老伙计。
- [bellows]
- [怒吼]
- Oh, fiddlesticks.
- 哦，小提琴。
- Rolly.
- 罗利。
I love your new look.
我喜欢你的新面貌。
- Mmm.
- 嗯。
- Aww.
- 哇。
So Rolly was an egg all along.
所以罗利一直都是个蛋。
- [meows]
- [喵]
- Rawr.
- Oh!
- 罗尔。
- 哦！
- Wow!
- 哇！
Now that's what I call a pet!
这就是我所说的宠物！
- [roars]
- [咆哮]
[burps]
[打嗝]
- Yay!
- 耶！
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
♪ ♪